<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title> - personal</title>
    <link href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk/tags/personal/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2026-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://carlocarfora.co.uk/tags/personal/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Claude Code After One Week</title>
        <published>2026-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2026-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/claude-code-after-one-week/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/claude-code-after-one-week/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After just over one week of Claud Code I felt compelled to write this blog post because of how much I feel the game has changed for myself since using this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The Landscape Has Changed</title>
        <published>2026-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2026-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/the-landscape-has-changed/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/the-landscape-has-changed/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First post of the year! Won&#x27;t jinx myself saying this is the first of many but let&#x27;s see how it goes 😆 Professionally been getting deep into USD and personally been exploring this thing called Clude Code...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A Look Back on 2025</title>
        <published>2025-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/a-look-back-on-2025/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/a-look-back-on-2025/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Trying to keep up tradition here and do a look back on 2025 as a year; mostly professional but with a bit of personal sprinkled in! If I could sum up 2025 in one word I think I&#x27;d have to go with the word &amp;quot;surprising&amp;quot; but even that feels a bit flat...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Added a Thumbnail Gallery</title>
        <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/added-thumbnail-gallery/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/added-thumbnail-gallery/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Small update to the website but a nice one, the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;carlocarfora.co.uk&#x2F;work&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Work&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; page now has shiny thumbnails for all the projects. Bit more visual now and it&#x27;s easier to click on everything that&#x27;s been done!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Kobo Libra Colour First Impressions</title>
        <published>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/kobo-libra-colour-first-impressions/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/kobo-libra-colour-first-impressions/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having bought a Kindle many years ago, I recently felt like it was time to upgrade it. I have had one without a backlight and found it could be tiring to read
at night. The e-reader market has so many choices now!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Coming Full Circle</title>
        <published>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/coming-full-circle/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/coming-full-circle/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, 2 years later and things come full circle! Just putting the finishing touches on a website makeover and hopefully making it something a bit less sterile.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>New Look, New Job</title>
        <published>2021-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/new-look-new-job/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/new-look-new-job/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s a new paint job over here! Moving over my static Github hosted website to Squarespace has been surprisingly painless. I am planning on cherry-picking a few of the previous blog posts to add as well and that should be it. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with a new look, after almost 4 1&#x2F;2 incredible years at The Mill I have made the decision to move on and was fortunate enough to land a role at Untold Studios where I’ll be continuing adventures as their Lighting Supervisor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt everything I know about VFX from my time at The Mill and am indebted to everyone there who I’ve worked with and learnt from. Even as the pandemic changed the nature of working The Mill has been nothing short of an incredible place to work and have fun while doing so.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All good things must come to an end though, and I’m beyond excited to continue working as Lighting Supervisor in a new environment with fresh challenges and faces!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>An end to a difficult year</title>
        <published>2020-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/an-end-to-a-difficult-year/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://carlocarfora.co.uk/blog/an-end-to-a-difficult-year/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another year, another complete lack of posts on here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could say it&#x27;s been 2020, that it&#x27;s been a difficult year and with everything happening in the world currently I&#x27;ve been feeling creatively empty... and while those things are true it&#x27;s also very true that I&#x27;ve just not given this the attention I would like to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a new laptop (oh hello Pixelbook and Chrome OS) that unchains me from the desk, there&#x27;s some renewed hope that this blog can be updated more regularly. Only time can tell!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-year-in-brief&quot;&gt;The Year In Brief&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In previous posts at the end&#x2F;start of a new year, looking back at the year has become something of a tradition. So, what has happened this year of note?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being promoted to Lighting and Rendering Supervisor at The Mill LDN has definitely been one of the career highlights this year, it&#x27;s been a role I&#x27;ve really enjoyed finding my feet in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing to push workflows forward, find more efficient ways of working and keeping up to date with what feels like the extreme forward momentum of the industry has been really exciting. It feels like this year has brought so many advances from Virtual Production to the latest software releases across DCC&#x27;s, there&#x27;s just so much going on at once it&#x27;s incredible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tranisitioning to working from home in our industry has been challenging for a lot of people, myself included. What began as the &amp;quot;dream&amp;quot; realised, quickly became extremely monotone and tiresome. While challenges such as using work infrastructure remotely and communications were ironed out, things like motivation and being able to switch off from work at home are tougher challenges that are individual to peoples circumstances.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenges of this year meant a quiet first half and insanely busy second half. Unfortunately, with companies having had to make the horrible decision of letting staff go this has meant that teams are smaller and having to work harder to keep up the workload. Burnout, fatigue and feeling overworked are things I&#x27;ve heard personally a lot this year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;looking-ahead&quot;&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While currently enjoying being switched off, it&#x27;s nice to have a moment to look ahead at what next year can hold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m personally excited to continue pushing forward with Solaris and USD, to try and find a workflow that works for us as a studio. It&#x27;s still an ongoing process but it&#x27;s looking extremely positive with Arnold and Solaris in tests so far.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realtime has made a huge impact this year, fingers crossed I can find myself on a few realtime projects next year to finally have an opinion on it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing to learn is always something I try to do, this year has felt like a refinement on existing knowledge so I&#x27;m keen to pick up something new next year!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s to seeing the back of a tremendously tough year and hopefully soon the start of a new one with brighter prospects for the world over.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
